Julien PLU

Research and development engineer

10 years of experience in various projects related to artificial intelligence on Natural Language Processing, in particular on the development of models and their deployment in production. Autonomous on my position while enjoying teamwork with on-site or remote collaborators.

Education

Doctorat en Informatique

Eurecom Sophia Antipolis / From July 2014 to December 2017 My thesis subject was to extract lexical units (entities) from textual documents in order to dissociate them from web resources contained in a knowledge base and in an adaptive way. This adaptivity concerns the language of the texts processed, the knowledge base used and the type of textual content.

Licence Informatique

Université Montpellier 2 Montpellier / From September 2007 to June 2010

Master Informatique, spécialité Intelligence Artificielle

Université Montpellier 2 Montpellier / From September 2010 to September 2012

Work experience

Research and development engineer

Buster.Ai Paris / Since October 2022

I am currently in charge of developing models for our fact-checking product. More specifically, my role is to train, evaluate, integrate and deploy these models in production.

• Research and development engineer

Beam Paris / From May 2021 to October 2022

I was responsible for training, optimizing and integrating machine learning model in a web browser. All of these models needed to run quickly on web browser users' machines. The web browser was exclusively developed for

Research and development engineer

Hugging Face Paris / From September 2020 to February 2021
I was in charge of all parts of the projects related to Tensorflow. I also had to write tutorials, make community on social networks, implement new Tensorflow models in the Transformers library and help users on the various Github repositories who had problems related to Tensorflow.

Research and development engineer

Leboncoin Paris / From April 2018 to August 2020

My role at Leboncoin was to develop new approaches and ideas involving Machine Learning and Natural Language Processing to improve the user experience.

Research and development engineer

Mondeca Paris / From January 2018 to March 2018
Assistance in the development of the company's internal software on Semantic Web technologies.

Developer

Aepsilon Sophia Antipolis / From April 2013 to June 2014 Consultant at Orange in Semantic Web and Natural Language Processing technologies for their internal Web search engine. I was mainly working on a question-answer engine based on DBpedia.



plu.julien@gmail.com

35 years old

https://jplu.github.io

French

🖼 Driving licence (B)

06 70 14 19 68

Civil union

Languages

English

Japanese

Skills

Machine Learning

Natural Language Processing

Semantic Web

Computer skills

Python

Java

Go

Misc

Kubernetes

Google Cloud Platform

Interests

Videogame

Scuba Diving

Guitare

Football

Social networks



🖣 @iplu

in @julienplu